# Justin Pritchard

Web Developer

## **Personal Info**

#### **Address**

174 Cooks Branch Rd Lynchburg VA 24501

#### **Phone**

308-641-2361

#### E-mail

jpritchard9518@gmail.com

#### Date of birth

6/4/1995

#### **Personal Website**

justinpritchard.net

#### LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/justin-pritchard-11a9b7a5/

#### Skills



Web Developer with 3 years part-time experience. I love to do both front end and back end work and seeing a project from conception to completion. My work is rooted in the desire to change lives while providing and analyzing data to inform smarter business decisions.

# **Experience**

Jun 2015 -Present

## **Web Development Intern**

American Center for Law and Justice (ACLJ)

- Worked with ACLJ development team creating, maintaining, and designing organization websites and applications
- Received extensive knowledge with Node.js, Javascript, HTML, CSS, React, React-Native, and MongoDB
- Full-stack development involving front-end, back-end, and database management
- Part of team that created mobile application using React-Native (2015)
- Primary developer for partner organization's website eclj.org (2016)
- Work on the admin/content management application
- Data analytics and reporting involving financials and member metrics reported to senior staff

Aug 2016 - May 2017

# Aug 2016 - May Web Developer

Liberty University School of Music

I worked with a team of students to create GLOW, a community service project for LU's School of Music. The project was a web application using Node.js, HTML, Mongodb, and AWS to host media from around the world.

Aug 2017 -Present

## Web and Mobile Developer

Liberty University Capstone

- Created application for organization working at refugee camps in Europe
- Developed application with Node.js as an interface for a Mongo database
- Developed React-Native (Android) application with external fingerprint connection to track recipient access when receiving materials from lines at a camp to prevent abuse of system

## **Education**

August 2013 -

## **Liberty University**

May 2018

BS in Computer Science

3.47 GPA

August 2009 -May 2013 Scottsbluff High School